<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<artists>
	<artist>
		<name>Neville Gabie</name>
		<extract>Working in a range of media from sculpture to film and photography, 
			Neville’s practice is focused on responding to locations which are in the process of change.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Born (1959) in Johannesburg, Neville Gabie studied at the Royal College of Art and has been based in Stroud, 
			Gloucestershire, for several years. Working in a range of media from sculpture to film and photography, 
			Neville’s practice is focused on responding to locations which are in the process of change. In practical terms 
			his work has been manifested as a series of temporary interventions made in response to specific locations or 
			situations. These sites are not arbitrary or randomly selected, but fit together, being places in a state of 
			physical or social flux. Projects are developed over a sustained period of involvement not just with the site, 
			but also with other creative professionals, making these works the result of intensive collaboration. Recent 
			residencies include: MOMART Tate Liverpool (1999); VitaminCreative Space, Gaungzhou, China (2004); and 
			International Art Space, Kellberrin, Western Australia (2006/7).  His work has been exhibited widely around 
			the world in galleries such as the Tate Modern in London, the Tate Gallery in Liverpool, the Metropolitan 
			Museum of Photography in Japan, and also as part of touring exhibitions in Germany, Japan, Macedonia, Portugal, 
			South Korea, and South Africa. Projects include ‘Further Up In The Air’ Liverpool (2001-05), which was developed 
			and curated jointly with Leo Fitzmaurice and COAST, Firstsite. Neville Gabie has also recently been selected to 
			be artist-in-residence with the British Antarctic Survey Expedition to Antarctica (2008-09).</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.nevillegabie.com</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Nayan Kulkarni</name>
		<extract>At the heart of his work 
			is an engagement with ideas of site specificity, time, technology and perception. These interests are manifested 
			in work that is generated from specific concepts, processes or places through diverse media such as light, video, 
			installation, sculpture and photography.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Multi-media artist Nayan Kulkarni (b. 1969) studied at the Slade School of Fine Art. At the heart of his work 
			is an engagement with ideas of site specificity, time, technology and perception. These interests are manifested 
			in work that is generated from specific concepts, processes or places through diverse media such as light, video, 
			installation, sculpture and photography. His studio work has been shown extensively in the UK and abroad and he 
			also develops curatorial and publication projects. His interest in the role of art as a means to transform public 
			spaces has resulted in the formation of NKProjects, a practice which enables the development of ideas relating to 
			site specificity and collaboration. Recent works include Nocturne a major lighting installation in Newcastle/Gateshead 
			and Sky Mirror in Birmingham. NKProjects is currently implementing; Shoal a major new light work for St Davids II, 
			Cardiff; Cascade a light and stone work for the Cathedral Green Regeneration, Derby; public realm lighting in Ashford; 
			Blink And Shimmer two new light based works for the Parkland Gateway Regeneration, Corby; Oasis: Five Gardens for Essex, 
			five landscape interventions as part of the Sadlers Farm Strategic Link improvements in Essex; Moment, a integrated 
			light and photographic work for Ikea, Southampton.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://nkprojects.co.uk</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Susanna Heron</name>
		<extract>Susanna Heron is an artist who has gained international recognition for her collaborations with architects and 
			large-scale site specific works since the completion of major commissions for The British Embassy in Dublin and 
			The Council Building for the European Union in Brussels in 1995.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Susanna Heron is an artist who has gained international recognition for her collaborations with architects and 
			large-scale site specific works since the completion of major commissions for The British Embassy in Dublin and 
			The Council Building for the European Union in Brussels in 1995.  Recent works include a major work of art entitled 
			'Still Point' for the garden of The Metropolitan Cathedral  Liverpool: the work takes the form of an 18 metre diameter 
			stone plinth, an engraved poem by the artist  and a song which was sung by the Cathedral choir at the inauguration 
			in 2007. The same year she collaborated with Levitt Bernstein Architects to make an exterior work which runs the 
			length of the Brunswick Centre  in Bloomsbury at the heart of the scheme. Other major collaborations include 
			'Side Street' for City Inn Westminster 2003, ‘The Phoenix Initiative’, Coventry 2003 (shortlisted for the Sterling Prize 
			2004), a five-storey structural  glass wall  '36 Elements: Glass Wall' for the Marunouchi Building in Tokyo 2002, and 
			‘The Sunken Courtyard’ for Hackney Community College, Hoxton 1997. From 1999-2005 she was Project Artist for Arnolfini 
			Capital Project, Bristol, collaborating on the design and advising on the space and function of the building as a member 
			of the Design Team. She was made an honorary Fellow of the Royal Institute of British Architects in 1999. Her studio-based 
			work is included in public collections internationally and she has had solo exhibitions at the Mead Gallery at 
			Warwick University, Camden Art Centre and Whitechapel Art Gallery amongst others. Susanna Heron has lived and worked in 
			the East End of London  since 1978. She occupied a SPACE Studio at Old Ford near the Olympic Site for 25 years and 
			recently moved into her own studio near north Brick Lane, a ten minute walk from Hoxton Square. She works closely with 
			her project manager Mary Hogben of Hogben and Hale Architects to procure her large scale works.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.susannaheron.com</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Vong Phaophanit &amp; Claire Oboussier</name>
		<extract>Vong Phaophanit and Claire Oboussier have worked together for over 20 years. 
			Their collaborative work encompasses, films, books, large- scale installations and sculptural works.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Based in London, Turner Prize Nominee (1993), Vong Phaophanit and Claire Oboussier have worked together for over 20 years. 
			Their collaborative work encompasses, films, books, large- scale installations and sculptural works. They have created a 
			number of large-scale groundbreaking public commissions. Recent works in the public realm include ‘Outhouse’ 2004, a 
			sculptural glass ‘abode’ for the collective use of local residents, sited within a public park for Liverpool Housing 
			Action Trust and ‘Topography of Dreams’ 2007, a temporary public installation which ‘inhabited’ the Grade 1 listed, disused 
			Curzon St. rail station in central Birmingham. Commissioned by Birmingham Arts Festival, the work gathered together the 
			hand-written ‘dream destinations’ of a cross-section of local residents which were scaled up reproduced exactly in neon. 
			Phaophanit and Oboussier are currently working on major public commissions for the Channel 4 Big Art Project (N. Belfast) 
			and the Foyle Public Art Project in Derry.  In addition to work within the public realm, they have exhibited their work 
			individually at venues such as Tate Britain, National Gallery of Canada, Ottowa, IMMA, Dublin, Reina Sofia Museum, Madrid, 
			the Shanghai Biennale, and the Void Gallery, Derry/Londonderry.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.atopia.org.uk</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Timorous Beasties</name>
		<extract>Timorous Beasties is noted for its surreal and 
			provocative textiles and wallpapers. By depicting uncompromisingly contemporary images on traditional textiles and 
			wallpapers, Timorous Beasties has defined an iconoclastic style of design once described as ‘William Morris on acid’.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>The name Timorous Beasties comes from Robert Burns’ poem ‘To A Mouse’. Founded in 1990 by Alistair McAuley and Paul 
			Simmons, both former textile design students at Glasgow School of Art, Timorous Beasties is noted for its surreal and 
			provocative textiles and wallpapers. By depicting uncompromisingly contemporary images on traditional textiles and 
			wallpapers, Timorous Beasties has defined an iconoclastic style of design once described as ‘William Morris on acid’. 
			Their work is as graphic and modern as it is varied, with designs ranging from target and arrow motifs to large 
			three-dimensional damasks. Their most notable designs feature swirling interpretations of naturalistic images of insects, 
			plants and fish to searing commentaries on social and political issues manifested through a subtly subversive take on 
			traditional graphic styles. They have designed for Boussac, Warner Fabrics, Liberty’s, and Sacho Hesslien. In 2005, 
			Timorous Beasties were nominated for Designer of the Year by the London Design Museum, and their work has been profiled 
			in numerous international media including The New York Times, Time Magazine, Vogue (UK, France, Italy and US editions), 
			Abitare, Elle Decoration, The Sunday Times, The Scotsman, Scotland on Sunday and The Financial Times.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.timorousbeasties.com/</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Claire Morgan</name>
		<extract>Claire Morgan is a visual artist with a strong interest in the organic, in natural processes, and in the bodily 
			connotations of natural materials.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Claire Morgan is a visual artist with a strong interest in the organic, in natural processes, and in the bodily 
			connotations of natural materials. This forms the basis for her practice as an artist creating sculptural installations 
			and continues to influence her work at present. Her installation, entitled ‘A New Moon’, involves a giant bulb suspended 
			from a tower crane and illuminated by hundreds of miniature lights mapping the contours of a four metre bulb. The 
			aspiration for this artwork was to generate a unique contrast against the winter sky, and to provoke and stimulate the 
			audiences that came into contact with the site. Previously, Claire’s work has been exhibited at the Saatchi Gallery in 
			October as part of a ‘reader-curated’ contemporary art show, after being voted as one of the UK’s leading emerging artists 
			by Guardian readers. Claire is preparing her first solo international show, currently in development with PIAC in Sicily. 
			Other recent commissions includes an aerial artwork for HLC, Telford; ‘Vital Signs’, an installation for Cardiff University 
			Optometry Building; design for light work for the Leicester Cultural Quarter Commissions Programme; and ‘Melt Down’ a 
			site-specific work in Blyth, Northumberland.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.claire-morgan.co.uk</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Esther Rolinson</name>
		<extract>Esther digitally animates found and self-generated 
			images and her work explores the architectural applications of three dimensional structures, animated light designs, and 
			digital technologies.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Esther Rolinson has been based in the South East region since 1993. She studied for her degree in Visual and Performing 
			Arts at Brighton University and since that time has worked solely as a visual artist working with three dimensional design, 
			gallery installations, digital imaging and architectural lighting. Esther has collaborated with professionals from a number 
			of other disciplines in the areas of architecture, landscape architecture, choreography and computer programming. Often 
			site-specific, her work focuses on the idea of sensitising environments. Esther digitally animates found and self-generated 
			images and her work explores the architectural applications of three dimensional structures, animated light designs, and 
			digital technologies. Esther has been a member of both the South East Regional Design Panel and the selection panel for the 
			Arts Council South East and SEEDA Awards for Art in Public Places. Her work includes: ‘Light Decks' at the Aquarium Terraces 
			Brighton, 2000; ‘Stream' on Hastings Promenade opened in 2003; and ‘Air Wave’ an articulate acrylic and light surface for 
			the Lookahead Housing Trust building in Bracknell. Esther continues to make interdisciplinary works and has an ongoing 
			collaborative relationship with Freemont Landscape Architects, initiated through an RSA Art for Architecture Award to carry 
			out an urban design study for Redhill. Esther Rolinson and Freemont Landscape Architects were members of the Buschow-Henley 
			Architect’s winning design team for the SEEDA international competition to create an innovative housing and landscape scheme 
			for St Mary's Island, Chatham Kent. Recent work includes: a large scale LED work for ‘Electric Wharf’, a power station under 
			development in Coventry; a light work embedded into the steps of the new Lewes Library;  and a temporary touring installation 
			‘Short Stay’ funded by Arts Council England.</p>
		</summary>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Dryden Goodwin</name>
		<extract>Central to his practice is a fascination with drawing, often combining drawing with photography, film and 
			large-scale screen-based installations with soundtracks. His work has explored the physical and emotional 
			dynamics of different environments, such as airports, hospitals, religious spaces, and city networks; 
			exploring their distinct qualities of time and space.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Dryden Goodwin (b. 1971) studied at the Slade School of Fine Art and lives and works in London. 
			Central to his practice is a fascination with drawing, often combining drawing with photography, film and 
			large-scale screen-based installations with soundtracks. His work has explored the physical and emotional 
			dynamics of different environments, such as airports, hospitals, religious spaces, and city networks; 
			exploring their distinct qualities of time and space. He is concerned with particular interactions between 
			people, frequently between himself and strangers. His work has been widely exhibited in the UK and abroad. 
			Solo exhibitions include Cast (Photographer’s Gallery, London, 2008), Flight (Feldman Gallery, Portland, 
			Oregon, USA, 2007), Sustained Endeavour: Portrait of Sir Steve Redgrave, (National Portrait Gallery, 2006), 
			Flight (Chisenhale Gallery, London, 2006), Draw In/Draw Out (New Art Gallery, Walsall, 2004), Dilate 
			(Manchester Art Gallery, 2003), Closer (Tate Britain, 2002). Group shows include Global Cities (Tate Modern, 
			2007), Strangers with Angelic Faces (Akbank, Istanbul, Turkey, 2006), Cross Town Traffic (Apeejay New Media 
			Gallery, New Delhi, India, 2005), Clandestine (50th Venice Biennale, Italy, 2003), A Century of Artists Film 
			in Britain (Tate Britain, 2003), Cathedral Camera (Baltic, Gateshead, 2003) and Reality Check (British Council 
			touring show 2002/04). Works in public collections include, The Museum of Modern Art in New York, Arts Council 
			of England and The National Portrait Gallery in London. He exhibits regularly with Stephen Friedman Gallery, 
			London. A new monograph will be published by Steidl &amp; Photoworks later this year.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.drydengoodwin.com</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Ackroyd &amp; Harvey</name>
		<extract>Sculpture, photography, biology and ecology are some of the disciplines that intersect into their work, revealing 
			an intrinsic bias towards process and event, often reflecting both architectural and scientific concerns.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Heather Ackroyd &amp; Dan Harvey are based in Surrey, England, and have collaborated internationally since 1990. 
			Sculpture, photography, biology and ecology are some of the disciplines that intersect into their work, revealing 
			an intrinsic bias towards process and event, often reflecting both architectural and scientific concerns. 
			They have shown in diverse contexts across the UK, Europe and the United States, including the Sculptural 
			Quadrennial, Riga (2004), Chicago Public Art Programme (2003), V&amp;A Museum, London (2000-1), World Expo, 
			Japan (2005), Big Chill Festival, UK (2007), and the Andalusian Centre for Contemporary Art, Seville (2007). 
			They have been recipients of numerous awards including the Wellcome Sci-Art Award and the NESTA Pioneer Award for 
			their work with the light sensitivity of seedling grass and its ability to record complex photographic images, 
			and have received two Art For Architecture awards from the Royal Society of Arts for the EPA Building, William 
			Dunn School of Pathology, Oxford, with Llewelyn Davis Architects, and Hanley Cultural Quarter, Stoke-on-Trent, 
			with Levitt Bernstein Associates. In 2007 they presented their largest installation to date on the exterior of 
			London’s National Theatre, where they grew the landmark Lyttleton flytower with seedling grass. Since 2003 they 
			have made a series of expeditions to the High Arctic with Cape Farewll, looking at the effects of climate change 
			on the ecosystem, and have shown the resulting work, a six metre long skeleton of a minke whale encrusted with alum 
			crystals, in group exhibitions at London’s Natural History Museum (2006), the Liverpool Biennial (2007), Fundacion 
			Canal, Madrid (2008), and Miraikan, Japan’s National Museum of Emerging Science &amp; Innovation, Tokyo (2008).</p>
		</summary>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Leo Fitzmaurice</name>
		<extract>His work is currently focused on the physical manifestations of information within our everyday environment. 
			He reworks advertising, signage, packaging and print to reveal other, often surprising, aspects of the 
			materials used within these various media which is so ubiquitous it is so often taken for granted.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Leo Fitzmaurice (b. 1963) studied at Leicester Polytechnic 1988-89, Liverpool Polytechnic 1989-92 and 
			Manchester Metropolitan University 1992-94, and currently lives and works in Heswall and Liverpool. 
			His work is currently focused on the physical manifestations of information within our everyday environment. 
			He reworks advertising, signage, packaging and print to reveal other, often surprising, aspects of the 
			materials used within these various media which is so ubiquitous it is so often taken for granted. 
			Most recently he has undertaken a series of interventions in public spaces in London, Liverpool, Norway, 
			#Berlin and Zurich for a commission called ‘Detourist’. Applying techniques of appropriation and reduction, 
			Fitzmaurice has subtly altered urban environments, adapting found materials and waste already at the sites in 
			question, or heightening existing forms by inserting handcrafted structures that started life as commercial 
			packaging. Other recent work includes: ‘Sometimes The Things You Touch Come True’, Yorkshire Sculpture Park 
			(2007); ‘You’ve Grown And Changed In So Many Ways’ (2006); ‘What Use Is A Sign If You Know The Way’, 
			Harewood House in Leeds (2005); and ‘Neat Stuff’, Firstsite Colchester (2005). With Neville Gabie, he was 
			co-curater of ‘ Further Up In The Air’ (2001-4) and has recently curated ‘Stuff Happens’ for the Angel Row 
			Gallery in Nottingham (2007).</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.leofitzmaurice.com</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Wolfgang Buttress</name>
		<extract>Working in a variety of materials including ferrous and non-ferrous metals, glass, concrete, stone and light, 
			Wolfgang Buttress has, over the last 15 years, produced artworks for the public realm in the UK, USA, Europe and 
			Japan.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Wolfgang Buttress (b. 1965) has a BA Hons in Fine Art from Trent Polytechnic and lives and works in Nottingham. 
			He creates simple, elegant and contextual public artworks which seek to define and celebrate a sense of place. 
			Working in a variety of materials including ferrous and non-ferrous metals, glass, concrete, stone and light, 
			Wolfgang Buttress has, over the last 15 years, produced artworks for the public realm in the UK, USA, Europe and 
			Japan. Inspired by the work of artists and architects such as Ando, Brancusi, Saarineen, Tapies and Twombly, 
			his work alludes to histories, traces and memories which are both personal and contextual. His experience 
			includes working collaboratively with a wide range of professionals, most recently with architects and 
			landscape architects such as Tadao Ando, BDP, and Conran and Partners.  His work has recently been exhibited at 
			the prestigious Wall Gallery, Tokyo; ABC Gallery, Fukuoka, Japan; and the Chicago Sculpture Biennales in 2006 and 
			2008. In March 2008, his ‘Silica’ landmark sculpture for the main shopping area of Weston-super-Mare was recognised 
			with a Civic Trust Award. The ovoid structure, which incorporates glass prisms and LED lighting, is composed of sand, 
			glass and stone, and houses a retail kiosk, a bus shelter and a public information display point within its base 
			before tapering dramatically into a spire. Commissioned by North Somerset Council, the sculpture represents a 
			ground breaking approach in public art where the artist has been responsible for selecting and appointing the team 
			of architects, engineers and contractors involved.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.wolfgangbuttress.com</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Marie-Jeanne Hoffner</name>
		<extract>Marie-Jeanne Hoffner’s drawings, wall drawings and architectural installations reflect a perception of space as map, 
			living space and place for the body. Her translation of space is both physical and metaphysical. On one hand, lines, 
			plans and volumes propose a concrete experience of space, whereas on the other, semantic superimposition and fake 
			perspective suggest an imaginary space that doubles our first apprehension of reality.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Marie-Jeanne Hoffner was born in 1974 in Paris. She is based in Paris and Châteauroux (France). 
			Since graduating in 1999 from the Nantes School of Art (ERBAN), she has shown her work in solo exhibitions in France 
			(Ipso Facto Gallery, Nantes, 2003; Collège Marcel Duchamp, Châteauroux, 2001, Art Centre Les Dominicaines in 
			Pont-L'évèque, 2005) as well as abroad (Arteaspoon gallery, Brussels, 2002; Glasgow Independent Studios, 2002, 
			Linden art Centre, Melbourne, Australia, 2006, Cast Gallery Hobart, Tasmania, 2007, Galeria Ernesto Catena, Buenos Aires, 
			2007). She has also participated in group exhibitions in Rennes, Nantes, Glasgow, Amiens, Paris,  and Malmö. 
			Several residencies in France include those at the Synagogue de Delmes art centre, and Parc St-Léger art centre, 
			while other intensive projects carried out during 2005 and 2007 include the Monash University visiting artist program 
			in Melbourne and at the Sydney College of the Arts, as well as RIAA, international residency program in Argentina. 
			Marie-Jeanne Hoffner’s drawings, wall drawings and architectural installations reflect a perception of space as map, 
			living space and place for the body. Her translation of space is both physical and metaphysical. On one hand, lines, 
			plans and volumes propose a concrete experience of space, whereas on the other, semantic superimposition and fake 
			perspective suggest an imaginary space that doubles our first apprehension of reality. The layout, removal, transparency 
			and folding of materials are recurrent notions in Hoffner’s work, allowing her to approach architecture through its 
			structural elements. This combination of formal rigour and physicality makes Marie-Jeanne Hoffner’s work an example of 
			lively practice both constructed and sensitive.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.mariejeannehoffner.org</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Ralph Hoyte</name>
		<extract>Bristol-based poet and text-based artist Ralph Hoyte created an exciting text-based work that captured and celebrated 
			Bristol and the development of Cabot Circus. This major artwork, on the hoardings around the Quakers Friars area of the 
			site, is one of the longest, site specific, text-based pieces in the country.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Bristol-based poet and text-based artist Ralph Hoyte created an exciting text-based work that captured and celebrated 
			Bristol and the development of Cabot Circus. This major artwork, on the hoardings around the Quakers Friars area of the 
			site, is one of the longest, site specific, text-based pieces in the country. The project, ‘Past-Present…Fuschia’, 
			intends to engage with the communities around Quakers Friars, its past and present history, and personal artistic concerns. 
			Ralph has also created a series of five text-based pieces depicting his interpretation of the name ‘Cabot’, which coincided 
			with the announcement of the new name for the development. Other recent or ongoing work includes ‘TALK TO ME’, three large-scale 
			(5m x 4m) permanent text-based wall mounted works as part of the fabric of the new Bristol Metropolitan College; a 
			collaboration with Michael Fairfax on a collection of eight metre high glass archways with embedded text and word inserts into 
			paving as part of environmental improvements in Heavitree, Exeter; and a commission to design ‘THE GARDEN OF THE FOUR JEWELS’ 
			in St Paul’s Bristol with Scott Farlow. Ralph Hoyte is also intensively developing new material inspired as a result of an 
			arts council-funded professional development trip to Japan, following in the footsteps of the 17th century Haiku Master, 
			Matsuo Basho (previewed at Tate Modern 2005), the first fruit of which is a book ‘HANA NO KAGE/SHADOW OF A FLOWER’. 
			Previous work includes: poet-in-residence for the Bristol Capital of Culture 2008 bid; launch poet for Legible City Bristol 
			(where he and Colin Pearce created ‘WALKIETALKIE’, a 600m long 'city epic' literally glued to the fabric of the city in the 
			form of a long leyline of text); creator of ‘1831 RIOT!’, the world's first located voice-play for mobile phone technology 
			in an intelligent environment based on the Queen Square Reform Riots of 1831; and writer-in-residence for English Heritage 
			at Tintagel Island, North Cornwall.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.ralphhoyte.net</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Blackout Arts</name>
		<extract>Art collective established in 2002 which evolved from Bristol’s 
			inspirational art enclave The Cube Cinema and which focuses on creating audio, visual and mixed-mode art works.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Rod Maclachlan works primarily will illumination and projection. He creates playful alchemy that explores the complementary 
			rhythms between imagination and observation, the subtle and the physical; the ethereal and the mundane. He studied sculpture 
			at Chelsea and Glasgow Art Schools and MA- Fine Art at University College Falmouth. Since arriving in Bristol in 1999 Rod has 
			been involved in the city’s thriving experimental video and film culture, and has worked on a number of video and light 
			installations, VJ activities, and the production design for arts events and music festivals. He recently collaborated with 
			Jem Noble on an audio-visual installation at the Tate Britain as part of the AV social event held there in April 2008. 
			Rod is one of three partners comprising Blackout Arts, the art collective established in 2002 which evolved from Bristol’s 
			inspirational art enclave The Cube Cinema and which focuses on creating audio, visual and mixed-mode art works.</p>
			<p>Jem Noble’s work brings together elements of intimacy and spectacle, aiming to produce encounters with immediate impact 
			that give way to multi-layered readings. Using sound and moving-image media to produce installations and performances in 
			response to site/situation, Noble is often concerned with the subversion of familiar objects, processes and experiences to 
			produce a sense of the uncanny, drawing out hidden complexities in relationships often taken for granted. Recent works include 
			Liberations (Spike Island, May 2008) – a solo exhibition of large-scale sculptural video projections with synchronous audio; 
			Underlap (Tate Britain, April 2008) – a responsive sound-design for Maclachlan’s video work; Dischord &amp; Dynne (Spike 
			Island, November 2007) – a six-point surround story telling in conjunction with Can Altay’s exhibition EY AHALI!; and I Dream 
			A Tower (Tollgate House, Bristol, 2006) – super-scale architectural video/radio installation as part of the Blackout Arts 
			public-art commission, intimate~INTIMATE. This work informs and echoes Noble’s parallel media practice which draws together 
			sound design, music production and video editing.</p>
			<p>The third member of Blackout Arts is Chiz Williams. No 7, number 9, twenty-one, page 2066. Numbers change as does the liquid 
			in our bodies. This former actor, ghostwriter, and international ice-cream sales person, re-values his relationship with the 
			arts at every lucky numerical point. Currently he is developing camera stock, exploring the aesthetics of Piracy, revisiting 
			a hazy and fantastical idea to make a feature film, coordinating music in tandem with location and staring into the sun as 
			every opportunity. A notorious and sticky collaborator whose best pieces are without notes. Chiz is a deep roller so - high 
			rise tumbles, low rent inferno's, the 'disco' and 'sport' all figure in his output when connected to the emotional. His work 
			within numerous artist groups over the last 25 years has been his main activity and he hopes this lasts another quarter.</p>
		</summary>
		<website>http://www.blackoutarts.co.uk</website>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Dan Perjovschi</name>
		<extract>He is now 
			known for his graffiti-like drawings that cover the walls and floors of art galleries around the world. His style resembles 
			the editorial cartoons that he produces for the newspaper, and the drawings often respond to divisions between the elite and 
			the disadvantaged masses in Romania, the constantly shifting boundaries and nature of the European Union, and the movements 
			of capital around the globe.</extract>
		<summary>
			<p>Dan Perjovschi (b. 1961, Romania). Lives and works in Bucharest. Since the overthrow of communism and the death of the 
			dictator Nicolae Ceausescu in the Romanian Revolution of 1989, Dan Perjovschi and his wife Lia have invested heavily in 
			establishing and promoting contemporary art in Romania. In 1991, he even joined the staff of Bucharest’s prominent opposition 
			newspaper, 22, as political illustrator and art director to increase his involvement in his country’s development. He is now 
			known for his graffiti-like drawings that cover the walls and floors of art galleries around the world. His style resembles 
			the editorial cartoons that he produces for the newspaper, and the drawings often respond to divisions between the elite and 
			the disadvantaged masses in Romania, the constantly shifting boundaries and nature of the European Union, and the movements 
			of capital around the globe. Infused with gossip, literary references, and witty punch lines, Perjovschi’s drawings deliver 
			their political message with generosity and humour.</p>
		</summary>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Lulu Quinn</name>
		<related>
			<artist>
				<name>Lulu Quinn &amp; Julie Westerman</name>
			</artist>
		</related>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
	<artist>
		<name>Lulu Quinn &amp; Julie Westerman</name>
		<related>
			<artist>
				<name>Lulu Quinn</name>
			</artist>
		</related>
		<casestudy>No</casestudy>
	</artist>
</artists>